Guide to the Rice University Vice President for Student Affairs records: Ronald Stebbings, 1969-1985 UA 216
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Vice President for Student Affairs records: Ronald Stebbings, 1969-1985
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University; Stebbings, Ronald F.
UA 216
1 Linear Feet (1 box)
This collection contains papers from Ronald Stebbings, former Vice President of Student Affairs. It includes minutes of faculty meetings of the entire university, as well as faculty meetings of the Space Physics and Astronomy program. It also contains various papers relating to the athletic committee, the publications Faculty Club Forum, and On Campus, and the Honor System. Also contains a photo directory of of faculty, research associates, students, and staff, as well as various items relating to the Space Physics and Astronomy program.
Biographical and Historical Note
Dr. Ronald F. Stebbings received his Ph.D. in atomic physics from University College London, in 1956. After receiving his degree, he worked at the Atomic Physics Laboratory in San Diego, California from 1958 to 1965. He returned to University College London in 1965, serving as a reader in physics there until 1968.
In the Fall of 1968, Dr. Stebbings joined the Rice University faculty as a professor, and later chairman, of the university's Space Physics and Astronomy department. From 1977 until 1982, Dr. Stebbings served as the Master of the Mary Gibbs Jones College, living in the residential college's master's home on campus with his wife and children during that period.
In 1983, Dr. Stebbings became the dean of undergraduate affairs, and on July 1, 1984 he was appointed Rice University's first Vice President for Student Affairs, by then president Norman Hackerman, joining three other administrators as the senior-most officials under the president. This change in title also involved a broadening of his responsibilities, as he became responsible for supervising the admissions, registrar's placement, and financial aid offices. This shift in responsibilites was done as an attempt to streamline the university's administration.
Dr. Stebbings served as Vice President for Student Affairs for ten years, before stepping down in 1993. After stepping down, he continued to work in Rice's Space Physics and Astronomy Department.
(Excerpted from Sallyport, April/May 1993, Feb/March 1984).
Scope and Contents
This collection contains papers from Ronald Stebbings, former Vice President of Student Affairs. It includes minutes of faculty meetings of the entire university (1969-1985), as well as faculty meetings of the Space Physics and Astronomy program (1971-1985). It also contains various papers relating to the athletic committee (1976-1983), and issues of "Faculty Club Forum," "On Campus," and the Honor System. Also contains a photo directory of of faculty, research associates, students, and staff, as well as various items relating to the Space Physics and Astronomy program.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Acquisition Information
This material was transferred to Woodson Research Center in August, 2010.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Document Types
letters (correspondence); directories; minutes (administrative records)
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University
- Rice University President For Student Affairs (Stebbings), 119825
  - Rice University Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1976-1984, 119826 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rice University Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1981-1985, 119827 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rice University Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1969-1979, 119828 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Space Physics and Astronomy Faculty Meetings, 1979-1985, 119829 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Space Physics and Astronomy Faculty Meetings, 1973-1974, 119830 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Space Physics and Astronomy Faculty Meetings, 1973, 119831 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Space Physics and Astronomy Faculty Meetings, 1971-1973, 119832 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Athletics Committee, 1976-1983, 119833 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Club Forum, On Campus, The Honor System, 119834 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photo Directory of Faculty and Research Associates, Students, and Staff, 119835 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Space Physics and Astronomy Information, 119836 (Box 1, Folder 11)